Guide to the Michael Robinson Papers MSS.494
Fales Library and Special Collections
Michael Robinson Papers
1969-2017
Fales Library and Special Collections
Robinson, Michael, 1956-
MSS.494
55.54 Gigabytes in 347 audio files and 1 archived website.
1 websites in 1 archived website.
55.54 Gigabytes in 347 audio files.
Michael Robinson is an American composer, performer, and musicologist whose works combine American, South Asian, and European traditions to create instrumental pieces. This collection contains an archived copy of his website, which features a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, examples of his works in the form of embedded video and audio files and prose writings, and images of Robinson. The collection also consists of 347 audio files representing the body of Robinson's musical work, including original and remastered recordings from 104 of his albums. Materials in the collection were created between 1969-2017.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information. If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials. If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to fales.library@nyu.edu. Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Arrangement
The collection was arranged in alphabetical order by title of project or publication, or format of material.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Michael Robinson, September 2016. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2017.048.
http://azuremilesrecords.com was selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2017.150.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
Scope and Contents
The Michael Robinson Papers contain an archived copy of his website, which features a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, interviews of and by the artist, examples of his works in the form of embedded video files and prose writings, and images of Robinson, who is a composer, performer, and musicologist. The collection also consists of 347 audio files representing the body of Robinson's musical work, including original and remastered recordings from 104 of his albums. Materials in the collection were created between 1969-2017.
Robinson's music, featured both on his website and the hard drive of audio files, is influenced by American, South Asian, and European musical traditions. It combines traditional instruments from many cultures with new performance techniques and electronic components. His website also includes his writings on the subjects of music, art, and basketball. The bulk of the images of Robinson featured on his site depict him at his home in Los Angeles.
Biographical Note
Michael Robinson is a prolific American composer who uses various instruments to create and perform his South Asian and European inspired music. Active since 1969, he has composed over 450 pieces on 113 albums. He has been a lecturer at such institutions as UCLA, Bard College, and California State University, and has produced a series of interviews with masters of various music styles. He currently lives in Los Angeles, California.
Conditions Governing Access
Sound recordings are available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval from the NYU Libraries based on a 2016 agreement with the donor.
Instrumental Music.; Music -- Southeast Asia; Sound recordings; Video recordings.; Web sites.; Digital images.
- The Abode of Joy (Remastered), December 11, 2011; FA_MSS_494_ER_1; 667.3 Megabytes in 9 audio files
  Conditions Governing Access
  Sound recordings are available for streaming with password authentification from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval from the NYU Libraries based on a 2016 agreement with the donor.
  Scope and Contents
  Album was remastered by Robinson in 2016.
  Songs were recorded between 1972-1984.
- The Abode of Snow (Remastered), December 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_2; 601.4 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Adorned with Pearl (Remastered), July 11, 1996; FA_MSS_494_ER_3; 536.1 Megabytes in 4 audio files.
  Songs were recorded between 1995-1996.
- African Pillows, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_4; 538.2 Megabytes in 9 audio files.
  Songs were recorded between 1991-1994.
- Amethyst Labyrinth (Remastered), June 1, 2011; FA_MSS_494_ER_104
- Astral Palace (Remastered), June 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_5; 611 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
  The album was remastered by Robinson in 2016.
- August, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_6; 600.9 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
  Songs were recorded in 1991.
- Bairagi (Remastered), November 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_7; 571.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Bhairava (Remastered), February 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_8; 516.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Bhairavi (Remastered), February 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_9; 448 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
  Song was recorded in 2009.
- Bhimpalasi (Remastered), September 27, 2001; FA_MSS_494_ER_10; 1.75 Gigabytes in 3 audio files.
  Album was remeastered by Robinson in 2016.
- Bhoop (Remastered), November 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_105
- Bouquet, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_11; 481.1 Megabytes in 10 audio files.
  Songs were recorded in 1990.
- Buki, November 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_12; 671.7 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
  Song was recorded in 1988.
- California Spring (Remastered), February 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_13; 573.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Carnelian Compass (Remastered), September 27, 2011; FA_MSS_494_ER_14; 276.7 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Celestial Crocodile and Honu Morning, August 4, 2016; FA_MSS_494_ER_15; 674.2 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Celestial Crocodile and Honu Morning (Remastered), August 4, 2016; FA_MSS_494_ER_16; 673.7 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Chakravaka (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_17; 133.1 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Charukeshi (Remastered), June 11, 2002; FA_MSS_494_ER_18; 608.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Chinese Legend (Remastered), October 11, 1997; FA_MSS_494_ER_19; 524.3 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Crayons, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_20; 512.5 Megabytes in 11 audio files.
  Songs were recorded from 1990-1991.
- Darbari Kanada (Remastered), December 11, 2006; FA_MSS_494_ER_21; 616.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Dark Yellow (Remastered), May 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_22; 510.3 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Dhani (Remastered), September 27, 2003; FA_MSS_494_ER_23; 1.98 Gigabytes in 3 audio files.
- Dharmavati (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_24; 385.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Dhirasankarabharanam (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_25; 388.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Earth's Pebbles, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_26; 517.8 Megabytes in 10 audio files.
  Songs were recorded from 1989-1991.
- Emerald Anklets (Remastered), December 11, 2011; FA_MSS_494_ER_27; 428.5 Megabytes in 3 audio files.
- The Fiddler of Dooney (Remastered), November 11, 2012; FA_MSS_494_ER_28; 304.5 Megabytes in 3 audio files.
- Fire Monkey (Remastered), January 11, 1994; FA_MSS_494_ER_29; 710.1 Megabytes in 8 audio files.
- The Forest (Remastered), December 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_30; 562.1 Megabytes in 8 audio files.
- Gamanapriya (Remastered), February 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_31; 453.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Gangadhara (Remastered), August 11, 2002; FA_MSS_494_ER_32; 532.5 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- The Girl in the Photograph (Remastered), September 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_33; 408.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Hamoa (Remastered), June 11, 1995; FA_MSS_494_ER_34; 695.9 Megabytes in 9 audio files.
- Hansadhvani (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_35; 386.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Hawaiian Rain, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_36; 581.5 Megabytes in 10 audio files.
  Songs were recorded between 1989-1990.
- Hummingbird Canyon, June 30, 2014; FA_MSS_494_ER_37; 470.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Hummingbird Canyon (Remastered), June 30, 2014; FA_MSS_494_ER_38; 432.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Indian Jasmine (Remastered), December 11, 1997; FA_MSS_494_ER_39; 628.4 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Indian Ocean (Remastered), June 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_40; 610.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Inspiration Point (Remastered), May 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_106
- Irish Ghost, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_41; 605 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Jaunpuri (Remastered), September 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_42; 614.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- The Jewel Treasure of the Ocean (Remastered), December 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_43; 462.8 Megabytes in 3 audio files.
- Kamavardhani (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_44; 410.5 Megabytes in 4 audio files.
- Kanakangi (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_45; 375.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Kaunsi Kanada (Remastered), June 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_46; 577.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Kirvani (Remastered), November 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_47; 540.6 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Kokilapriya (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_48; 379 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Lahaina Lanterns (Remastered), March 11, 2013; FA_MSS_494_ER_49; 443.9 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Latangi (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_50; 423.9 Megabytes in 3 audio files.
- Like Rain, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_51; 534.1 Megabytes in 9 audio files.
- Lilac Dawn, June 19, 2017; FA_MSS_494_ER_52; 446.6 Megabytes in 3 audio files.
- Lilac Dawn (Remastered), June 19, 2017; FA_MSS_494_ER_53; 446 Megabytes in 3 audio files.
- Lion Dance, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_107
- Listening Earth (Remastered), November 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_108
- The Lotus Girl (Remastered), December 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_54; 636.8 Megabytes in 9 audio files.
- Lucknow Shimmer (Remastered), November 11, 2013; FA_MSS_494_ER_109
- Luminous Realms (Remastered), July 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_55; 609.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Lunar Mansions (Remastered), March 11, 1998; FA_MSS_494_ER_56; 589.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Madhmad Sarang (Remastered), February 11, 2001; FA_MSS_494_ER_57; 571 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Mian ki Malhar (Remastered), January 11, 2003; FA_MSS_494_ER_58; 555.4 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Monsoon Clouds (Remastered), February 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_59; 610.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Moonrise and Rain-Mist, December 17, 2015; FA_MSS_494_ER_60; 556.6 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Moonrise and Rain-Mist (Remastered), December 17, 2015; FA_MSS_494_ER_61; 556.4 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Movement of Time, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_62; 569.1 Megabytes in 10 audio files.
- Nagamani (Remastered), July 11, 1998; FA_MSS_494_ER_110
- Nat Narayan (Remastered), July 11, 2006; FA_MSS_494_ER_63; 509.6 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Natabhairavi (Remastered), October 21, 2015; FA_MSS_494_ER_64; 585.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Night of Fire (Remastered), December 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_65; 553.3 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Nightmarches (Remastered), March 11, 2012; FA_MSS_494_ER_66; 316.3 Megabytes in 3 audio files.
- North Africa (Remastered), December 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_67; 516.3 Megabytes in 6 audio files.
- Onyx Sands (Remastered), October 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_68; 400.3 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Patdeep, Jait, Magh (Remastered), May 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_69; 659.2 Megabytes in 3 audio files.
- Peridot Pond (Remastered), February 11, 2011; FA_MSS_494_ER_70; 404.7 Megabytes in 4 audio files.
- Photosynthesis (Remastered), December 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_71; 535.5 Megabytes in 6 audio files.
- Pink Monkey (Remastered), September 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_72; 413.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Pink Sapphire (Remastered), October 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_111
- Polynesian Woman (Remastered), December 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_73; 659.5 Megabytes in 10 audio files.
- Portrait, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_74; 488.5 Megabytes in 9 audio files.
  Songs were recorded between 1989-1991.
- Puriya Dhanashri (Remastered), February 11, 2002; FA_MSS_494_ER_75; 695.6 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Purple and Brown (Remastered), December 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_76; 678.5 Megabytes in 10 audio files.
- Rageshri (Remastered), March 11, 2001; FA_MSS_494_ER_77; 566 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Rainbow Thunder (Remastered), December 11, 1996; FA_MSS_494_ER_112
- Rajasthani Spring, June 11, 2015; FA_MSS_494_ER_78; 325.6 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Rajasthani Spring (Remastered), June 11, 2015; FA_MSS_494_ER_79; 325 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Ramapriya (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_80; 428.5 Megabytes in 3 audio files.
- Robinson Gardens (Remastered), December 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_81; 572.7 Megabytes in 5 audio files.
- Ruby Cars, June 23, 2017; FA_MSS_494_ER_82; 607.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Ruby Soul (Remastered), July 11, 2012; FA_MSS_494_ER_83; 204.8 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Rusabhapriya (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_84; 385.5 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Sagarmatha (Remastered), June 11, 1998; FA_MSS_494_ER_85; 611.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Sea of France (remastered), July 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_113
- Shankara (Remastered), September 11, 2006; FA_MSS_494_ER_86; 508.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Snow and Wood (Remastered), December 11, 2000; FA_MSS_494_ER_87; 689.9 Megabytes in 10 audio files.
- Snow Leopard Meadow (Remastered), March 11, 1999; FA_MSS_494_ER_88; 610.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- The Spirit Pool, November 11, 2014; FA_MSS_494_ER_92; 424.5 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- The Spirit Pool (Remastered), November 11, 2014; FA_MSS_494_ER_96
- Summer Morning (Remastered), September 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_89; 404.8 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Teahouse, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_90; 504.7 Megabytes in 8 audio files.
- Tendrils (Remastered), December 11, 1995; FA_MSS_494_ER_91; 709.5 Megabytes in 4 audio files.
- Todi (Remastered), December 11, 2006; FA_MSS_494_ER_93; 586.2 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Topaz (Remastered), May 10, 2017; FA_MSS_494_ER_94; 346.5 Megabytes in 5 audio files.
- Touch a Color (Remastered), September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_95; 659 Megabytes in 7 audio files.
- Trembling Flowers (Remastered), July 11, 1991; FA_MSS_494_ER_97; 756.8 Megabytes in 11 audio files.
- Vachaspati (Remastered), May 11, 2005; FA_MSS_494_ER_98; 607.9 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Wine Breath, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_99; 558.9 Megabytes in 10 audio files.
  Recordings for this album were made between 1991-1992.
- Wings of the Owls, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_100; 613.1 Megabytes in 2 audio files.
- Yaman (Remastered), June 11, 2006; FA_MSS_494_ER_101; 609.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Yellow and Black, September 15, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_102; 611.4 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Yellow Silk, November 11, 2010; FA_MSS_494_ER_103; 634.3 Megabytes in 1 audio file.
- Archived Website, May 2017-ongoing; cuid6061
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://azuremilesrecords.com and issuu.com/azuremiles/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his compositions, a discography of his published works, Robinson's prose works, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files. Robinson's acoustic music is inspired by American, South Asian, and European traditions, and incorporates Indian ragas. Capture of the site began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.